MAKSIM POSTNIKOV

Coquitlam, BC | max@postnikov.dev | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

Frontend developer with 5+ years of experience in designing and building integration-ready, user-friendly web applications using a wide range of technologies such as React, TypeScript, TailWind, Bootstrap, and other modern tools and frameworks. Proficient in building software from scratch and working with legacy code. Innovation-driven problem solver with a focus on user experience improvement and customer engagement.

KEY COMPETENCES

- Responsive Web Design & Mobile First Approach
- WCAG & ADA Web Accessibility Compliance
- Cross-browser Compatibility
- Version Control / Git
- Web App Performance & Durability Optimization
- Testing Automation and Code Debugging
- Backend Foundational Principles
- Agile / Scrum Methodology
- Work Independently or as a Part of the Team
- CI/CD practice

TOOLS

Development Stack: HTML/CSS, JS, TypeScript, React, Redux, MongoDB, Express, NodeJS, REST API, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Gulp, Twig, Webpack, GIT, Docker, BEM, SPA, AWS services, CraftCMS, JEST, PWA, ES6, ESLint, SQL.

Methodologies: Agile (Scrum), Waterfall, Kanban.

PM Tools: CRM, Jira, Confluence, Trello, Notion, Slack, G-suite

WORK EXPERIENCE

WISEUP STUDIO SC, USA

Frontend Developer Mar 2020 – Aug 2023

Built websites, PWA, and specific interactive components. Provided code review. Applied frameworks and libraries (React/Redux, Bootstrap, Tailwind) and bundlers (Gulp, Webpack) and used pure HTML, CSS, and TS. Followed best practices using BEM, Responsive Web Design, and Mobile First application principles. Created MERN-based backend and REST API for web apps.

- Developed websites from the concept stage using HTML, SCSS, and TypeScript based on Gulp+TWIG or Webpack+React, created templates and maintained CraftCMS-based websites;
- Applied responsive design techniques to view websites on any device, increasing mobile traffic by 60%;
- Optimized image loading and created SPA, improving sites loading speed up to 35%;
- Implemented Progressive Web Applications technology, increasing user satisfaction to 95%;
- Updated REST APIs, reducing network traffic by 65% and improving app performance by 25%;
- Implemented cache strategy, reducing the number of MongoDB requests by 90%.
- Used AWS to create a NodeJS-based backend, reducing annual maintenance costs by 60%;
- Conducted peer code reviews and integrated TypeScript, cutting user error reports by 35%;
- Boosted code efficiency by 25% by identifying and fixing performance bottlenecks;
- Followed accessibility website standards to meet WCAG & ADA compliance;

Junior Frontend Developer

Jan 2019 - Feb 2020

Built websites using pixel-perfect and adaptive design in collaboration with designers and senior developers. Created mocks. Participated in code reviews and worked with senior developers.

- Developed and maintained websites using HTML/CSS/JS and Bootstrap/Gulp/TWIG;
- Created adaptive design, using BEM and ES6 to meet the high development standards;
- Developed code to convert design wireframes and mock-ups into pixel-perfect website elements;
- Participated in code reviews and worked with senior developers to improve code quality;

ECOSTROY Irkutsk, Russia

System Engineer

Jun 2015 - Jan 2019

Created an IT development strategy, configured security settings and access permissions for individuals and groups. Implemented complex virus malware protection plan. Communicated with third-party System Engineer Groups to create optimal solutions for the business needs.

- Created and implemented an enterprise disaster prevention and recovery strategy;
- Established response standards for day-to-day servers, network, and data backup system operational support;
- Introduced a set of technological tools, optimizing operational efficiency by 30%;
- Integrated a series of business operations software, reducing data entry mistakes by 80%;

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING AND EDUCATION

Professional Scrum Master, PSM-II, Certificate Scrum.org, 2023

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, <u>AWS CCP</u>, Certificate AWS, 2022

Frontend Web Developer, Certificate
SkillFactory Educational Platform, 2019

Major in Computer Information Systems, Master's Degree

Baikal State University, Russia